https://seg.org/privacy-policy

Donor Information
Why/How to Donate?
eNewsletters
SEG Advanced Modeling (SEAM)
SEAM Projects
Phase I (Subsalt)
Management Committee
Technical Committee
Project Manager
RPSEA Partnership
Phase II (Land)
Editors and Staff
JEEG (EEGS)
Receive Assistance
Dues Waiver ProgramGroup Insurance ProgramDiscounted SEG ProgramsMembers in Transition
Donor Information
Why/How to Donate?Donor Giving Club LevelsDonor Recognition Lists
Donate NowAnnual Reports/FinancialsSpecial Giving Opportunities
Governance
Annual ReportsArticles of IncorporationBoard of DirectorsCode of EthicsCommitteesSEG BylawsSEG Council
What this policy covers
Your privacy is important to the Society of Exploration Geophysicists, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use, and share information about you. This policy is intended to help you understand:
What information we collect about you
How we use information we collect
How we share information we collect
How we store and secure information we collect
How to access and control your information
How we transfer information we collect internationally
Other important privacy information
This Privacy Policy covers the information we collect about you when you use our products or services or otherwise interact with SEG (for example, attending SEG events), unless a different privacy policy is displayed. This policy also explains your choices about how we use information about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you.
What information we collect about you
Account and Profile information: We collect information about you when you apply for membership, create or modify an account, create or modify your Member Search profile-display settings; set communication preferences; participate as a speaker, author, SEG Wiki contributor, or volunteer (through SEG’s online volunteer registry); and when you register for, subscribe to, or otherwise purchase SEG products and services.
Payment information: We collect certain payment and billing information, such as payment card details, which we collect and process in accordance with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard. When you designate a billing representative, we collect personal information about that representative including name and contact details.
Cookies and other tracking technologies: SEG and our third-party analytics partners use cookies to provide improved functionality and analytical data. For more information, please see our Cookie Policy.
How we use information we collect
To provide services and personalize your experience:  We use information about you to authenticate you when you sign in and to send you information, according to your communication preferences, that you have given SEG specific consent to deliver to you. We will update you regarding the delivery of products or services you may expect from SEG. This includes notification of new membership benefits you may qualify for such as a free associate membership after graduation or emeritus membership based on your birth date and years of membership. We also will contact voting Members regarding elections, scholarship and travel-grant applicants with updates related to the awarding process, and Members and customers regarding the status of orders for products and services.
For research and development: We always are looking for ways to make our products and services smarter, faster, more secure, and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people use our services, plus survey feedback provided directly to us, to troubleshoot and to identify trends, usage, activity patterns, and areas for improvement in SEG products and services. This means we don’t identify you individually but look at visitors as a whole to help us identify ways we can improve how we interact and communicate with you. For more information, see our Cookie Policy.
To market, promote and drive engagement: We use your contact information and your communication preferences to send newsletters and promotional communications that you have given your consent to receive. The communications are aimed at driving engagement and maximizing what you get out of SEG. You can control what communications you receive from us by signing in to your account online and managing your communication preferences in our communications center. You may also contact us.
How we share information we collect
Third parties performing services: We employ the services of third-party processors in order to deliver quality products and services to you. Your information is shared at the time you elect to utilize the benefits of those services. Only the minimum information necessary to fulfill those services is shared with the third-party processors. For example, when you elect to receive communications through your communication preferences center, we share your contact information and preferences with our email marketing service provider for the delivery of specific emails. If you take a competency test in our Competency Management System, your information is provided to the competency management processor for the sole purpose of delivering the competency test, results, and support services. If you publish through the SEG or serve as an editor or reviewer of SEG publications, your information is provided to vendors that provide publishing services. Third-party processors with whom we may share your information for the purpose of providing services to you include but are not limited to those supporting our email marketing, competency management, publishing activities, online collaboration, on-demand learning, online content delivery, surveys, career center, scholarship and/or travel-grant applications, and mobile applications. When you use these systems, only the information absolutely necessary to deliver the product or service is provided and is returned to SEG or deleted. Your information is not used for any other purpose.
SmartBrief newsletter: We partner with SmartBrief to deliver a free industry-focused email newsletter to our customers. Campaigns run every four months, and new customers of SEG are automatically added to the new subscriber campaign. SEG will securely transfer email addresses of new customers to SmartBrief, and you will receive the SEG SmartBrief newsletter for a trial period of two weeks. You will continue to receive the SEG SmartBrief newsletter if you agree to subscribe by visiting the SmartBrief website and providing your email address. You may receive additional trials of the SEG SmartBrief newsletter if you do not unsubscribe to the SEG SmartBrief emails. If you unsubscribe, you will not receive future SEG SmartBrief campaigns. You may learn more about your data usage in the SmartBrief privacy policy.
Third-party marketers/SEG partners: We do not share your information with third-party direct marketers or SEG partners for any reason except if you register through SEG for a partnered event. In those cases, we will transfer your registration and contact information securely to the host or partner of the event. If you do not wish to hear from SEG about products and services that SEG partners offer, please do not opt in to SEG Partner Events in your communications center.
Third-party advertisers: We do not share personal data with the advertisers for any advertisements that are displayed on our website. We do use a third-party service to provide such ad functionality, but personal information is not shared that would identify you.
Exhibitors/sponsors: Exhibitors and event sponsors are provided a list containing first name, last name, and company name of all registered attendees before and after an event. Contact information is provided only if attendees allow an exhibitor to scan their event badge.
Hotel/housing providers: Housing providers and contracted hotels are provided a list containing first and last names of all registrants for an event. The information is reconciled against the hotel registrations in order for SEG to obtain housing block credit. We partner with hotels in order to provide attendees with discounted housing rates during SEG events.
Company controllers: Company controllers are able to register you, on your behalf, for an event as an employee or guest of their company. A company controller is required to enter your name and email address. If we find a match on email address, that registration will be added to your account history, but no personal information is shared with the company controller (in most cases an employee of an exhibiting company) other than the data the controller entered. If an email match is not found, a new account is created and you will receive an email indicating the order was processed on your behalf. You may then access your account online and manage your account at any time. Please see the How to access and control your information section below.
SEG Member Search: All SEG Members receive a profile that appears in the SEG Member Search online. Your member profile is automatically populated with information you provide, including your name, membership status, business address, business phone, business fax, and primary email. Additional profile information is available to be populated by you. You may elect to hide or display your entire profile or select only certain fields to display via your “My Account.” All members will be able to view your full profile, according to your privacy settings. The public is able to view basic information (name, city, country) within the Member Search results if display of your profile is enabled.
Volunteers/committees: Committee members and Society volunteers will receive contact information necessary to fulfill the responsibilities of the Society. Membership-application information such as first name, last name, employer, title, and experience is provided to the Membership Committee for approval of applicants for Active Membership. First name, last name, and email for all volunteers agreeing to participate as an abstract reviewer within the past two years will be provided to volunteer key contacts. Key contacts will then use this contact information to directly solicit review services for the upcoming year.
How we store and secure information we collect
Data retention: We retain your contact information and transaction history with SEG for as long as necessary to support the legitimate interests of the Society for the duration of business or contractual relationships, to maintain historical records of transactions, and to fulfill legal requirements.
Security: We take technical, physical and administrative measures to safeguard the confidentiality, integrity and availability of the data you provide to SEG. We take similar measures to evaluate the security of the third party processors we employ.
How to access and control your information
My Account: You may access your account online upon successful sign in to update your contact information, view your membership summary, manage your communication preferences, manage your privacy settings, manage which aspects of your profile will be displayed in Member Search results, manage your volunteer profile, and view your purchase and donation history. If you have further questions about your data or object to certain forms of processing, you may contact us.
How we transfer information we collect internationally
Our main business office and our website hosting and data centers are located in the United States. We have regional offices in China and the United Arab Emirates. Your information is securely shared among our offices in order to deliver products and services to you.
Other important privacy information
Our policy toward children: Our services are not directed to individuals under 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information, please contact us.
Contact Us
If you have further questions about your data, or objecting to certain forms of processing you may contact us by post at:
Society of Exploration Geophysicists
8801 S. Yale Ave. Suite 500
Tulsa, OK 74137
or by email at [email protected].
ADVERTISEMENT
Our advertisers help SEG provide services to our customers. Please consider unblocking ads for our site.
This website uses cookies. If you continue without changing your browser settings, you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with our cookie policy. You can disable cookies at any time. Learn more
We also use partner advertising cookies to deliver targeted, geophysics-related advertising to you; these cookies are not added without your direct consent.
Allow Partner Advertising Cookies OK, I understand
8801 S. Yale Ave. Suite 500
Tulsa, OK 74137
Phone: 918-497-5500
Email: [email protected]
Don't miss a thing.
Visit your SEG Communications Center to update your communications preferences.
Don't have an SEG account? It's free to create one - and you don't have to be an SEG member.
THE LEADING EDGE DIGITAL EDITION
Featuring bonus content!
© 1996-2020 Society of Exploration Geophysicists | All Rights Reserved
